<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Emacs on Kiran Gangadharan</title><link>http://kirang.in/tags/emacs/</link><description>Recent content in Emacs on Kiran Gangadharan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kirang.in/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up Org-mode to run Clojure code</title><link>http://kirang.in/post/setting-up-org-mode-to-run-clojure-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://kirang.in/post/setting-up-org-mode-to-run-clojure-code/</guid><description>I wanted to be able to store interesting clojure snippets in an org file and then execute and play with them without leaving the file. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate the steps needed to achieve the same. I am assuming that you&amp;rsquo;ve already setup Emacs with org-mode and cider.
First, start by installing the ob-clojure package:
M-x package-install ob-clojure or simply do so with use-package:
1 (use-package ob-clojure) Now we need to let org-mode know to use a cider repl to execute the snippets in our file:</description></item><item><title>My eshell prompt setup</title><link>http://kirang.in/post/eshell-prompt-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://kirang.in/post/eshell-prompt-setup/</guid><description>My setup is based on Howard Abrams&amp;rsquo; setup with some minor additions and is reproduced in its entirety here:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 (defun curr-dir-git-branch-string (pwd) &amp;#34;Returns current git branch as a string, or the empty string if PWD is not in a git repo (or the git command is not found).</description></item><item><title>Setting up org-mode pdf export in OS X ElCapitan</title><link>http://kirang.in/post/setting-up-org-mode-pdf-export-in-osx-elcapitan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://kirang.in/post/setting-up-org-mode-pdf-export-in-osx-elcapitan/</guid><description>Basic TeX Download and install Basic TeX package from here.
Set System Path The package will be installed at /Library/TeX/texbin/, so it must be added to your PATH like so:
1 export PATH=$PATH:/Library/TeX/texbin Run which latex to ensure that the path has been set correctly.
Install Dependencies You&amp;rsquo;re not ready yet. There are a few more packages that need to be installed in order to render the pdf from the tex file.</description></item><item><title>Emacs as email client with offlineimap and mu4e on OS X</title><link>http://kirang.in/post/emacs-as-email-client-with-offlineimap-and-mu4e-on-osx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 02:06:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://kirang.in/post/emacs-as-email-client-with-offlineimap-and-mu4e-on-osx/</guid><description>Introduction For something as trivial and important as email, it annoys me that I feel uncomfortable with any client I use. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the Gmail interface, Mail.app, Airmail and Mailbox, but somehow I haven&amp;rsquo;t found myself entirely comfortable using any of these. What I&amp;rsquo;m looking for is a client that is easy to shoot up, quick to navigate between emails and can entirely depend on keyboard shortcuts alone. In short email on the terminal.</description></item></channel></rss>