<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code on Kiran Gangadharan</title>
    <link>http://kirang.in/tags/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code on Kiran Gangadharan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 02:56:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kirang.in/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Familiarising yourself with a large codebase</title>
      <link>http://kirang.in/post/familiarising-yourself-with-a-large-codebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 02:56:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kirang.in/post/familiarising-yourself-with-a-large-codebase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure that a lot of developers find it harder to read existing code&#xA;and understand the ideals behind it, rather than writing it from&#xA;scratch, themselves. I too have this same problem, and so started&#xA;looking around online as to how people have dealt with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled&#xA;some good answers from various sources, below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Try and understand at a high level, what the purpose of the code is, and then identify the key elements/functions that help achieve this purpose&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Try to read as much design and documentation about the project&#xA;before diving in&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Try and figure out the relations between various components and then&#xA;draw/visualise an architecture diagram&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk to authors and clarify things with them beforehand&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Go through unit tests to get a high level overview&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start with the entry point in the program. This will in turn point&#xA;to what gets started and sometimes how things are linked.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make small edits or bug fixes, then gradually build up&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep notes. Don&amp;rsquo;t jump in and start developing; it&amp;rsquo;s more valuable&#xA;to spend time understanding than to generate messy or inappropriate&#xA;code.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope you find success after following the above tips :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
